let's go over how to write and use an
让我们先来学习如何编写和使用数组。
array in solidity first we'll go over
how to write an array now an array has
现在如何写数组数组具有三个内置功能push / pop
three built-in functionalities push/pop
in length so you'll go over some
篇幅较长，因此您将分别使用每个示例以及
examples using each of them and for the
last example I'll show you how to remove
最后一个例子，我将向您展示如何从数组中删除元素以声明
an element from array to declare an
array you start with the type of array
数组以要创建的数组类型开头，后跟一个
that you want to create followed by a
pair of brackets for our example you'll
在本例中，您将创建一系列联合国的
create an array of UN's
so we start with the type of the array
所以我们从数组的类型开始，它是U，然后是一对
which is U and followed by a pair of
brackets and then we declare the name of
中括号，然后我们声明数组的名称，在这种情况下，我将其命名为
the array in this case I'll name it my
array for this example we want to be
对于此示例，我们希望能够从外部访问该数组
able to access this array from outside
the contract so we will declare this
合同，所以我们将这个数组声明为public，就是这样
array as public and that's it this is
how you would create an array of type
现在如何创建类型为int的数组
int now arrays can be either dynamically
sized or fixed size where you declare
大小或固定大小，您可以在编译时声明该数组的大小
the size at compile time this array that
we just created is dynamically sized
我们刚刚创建的是动态调整大小的，这意味着数组的大小
which means that the size of the array
can change after the contract is
在编译合同以创建固定大小的数组后可以更改
compiled to create a fixed sized array
you declare the size of the array inside
您在方括号内声明数组的大小，这里我创建了一个固定的
the brackets here I've created a fixed
size array of type U n where the size is
类型为U n的size数组，其大小固定为10，因此此数组有10
fixed to ten so this array has ten
elements and you won't be able to change
元素，您将无法更改每个元素的数组大小
the size of the array each element of
the array is initialized to its default
数组被初始化为其默认值，类型为youant
value the default value of type youant
is zero so when the contract is created
为零，因此在创建合同时，此数组将是包含十个数组的数组
this array will be an array with ten
zeros now you can also initialize an
现在为零，您也可以在此处使用默认值初始化数组
array with default values like this here
we've created a dynamic array of type
我们创建了一个类型为youant的动态数组，并存储三个值一二
youant and store three values one two
and three into this array so that covers
和三个放入此数组，以便涵盖如何编写动态大小和固定大小的
how to write dynamic sized and fixed
sized arrays next let's go over how to
大小的数组接下来，让我们讨论如何在数组推送的长度内使用push / pop
use push/pop in length of an array push
is a function that
是将元素添加到数组末尾的函数
adds an element to the end of the array
now to show you example how to use push
现在向您展示如何使用推的示例，我将首先创建一个公共函数
I'm gonna first create a public function
that we can call from remix we're gonna
可以从混音中调用的函数，我们将其命名为push并将其命名为
name this function push and it's gonna
take in the number that we're gonna push
接受我们将要加入联合国的人数，以推动我们的组成部分
into the UN already to push our element
into an array you call the push method
到数组中，您可以在数组中调用push方法，并传入以下元素：
on the array passing in the element that
you're gonna push for this example we're
您将在本示例中进行推送，我们将调用push方法可能数组
gonna call the push method might array
and this will depend on signed integers
这将取决于有符号整数到数组的末尾接下来我们开始
to the end of the array next let's go
over pop called him pop on array would
over pop叫他pop on array会删除数组中的最后一个元素，并且
remove the last element in the array and
we're also gonna wrap this in a public
我们还将把它包装在一个公共函数中，以便我们对其进行测试
function so that we could test it out
from remix and we're gonna call this
从混音开始，我们将这个功能称为“ pop”
function pop inside the function it's
gonna call the pop method on my array in
要在最后一个内置功能中调用数组上的pop方法
the last built-in functionality
available to arrays in solidity is the
可用于数组的长度属性是length属性，length属性是
length property the length property
stores the length of the array we're
存储数组的长度，我们也将其包装在公共场合
also gonna wrap this in a public
function so that we could get the length
函数，以便我们可以获取数组的长度
of the array
now come
现在来部署合同，让我们看看
and deploy the contract and let's see
some examples of push pop and length
一些推送弹出和长度的示例，让我们推送一些我要推送的数字
let's push some numbers I'm gonna push
one two and three now that we push three
一二和三现在我们推三个元素一二和三的长度
elements one two and three the length of
the array should be three and you can
该数组应为3，并且您可以检查我的数组是否存储1和2
check that my array stores one two and
three by getting each element by the
如果您尝试获取一个元素，则通过按索引获取每个元素来获取三个元素
index now if you try to get an element
that is out of bound
那是越界的，您会在这里收到这样的错误
you'll get an error like this here the
array has three elements so the last
数组具有三个元素，因此最后一个元素存储在索引2中，当我们
element is stored at index 2 and when we
try to get the element at index 3 we get
尝试获取索引3处的元素，我们得到一个错误
an error
next let's try calling pop several times
接下来，让我们尝试在调用pop 1时多次调用pop，它应该删除
when you call pop 1 it should remove the
last element so the length of the array
最后一个元素，因此数组的长度现在应该为2，而我们的元素应该
should now be 2 and our elements should
be 1 and 2 and if you call pop on an
是1和2，如果您在一个空数组上调用pop，并且抛出了空气，那么我
empty array this with thrown air so my
array has two elements and calling pop
数组有两个元素，第三次调用pop将失败
the third time will fail
since my array is empty now donate for
由于我的数组为空，现在捐赠的加薪应该为0，
the raise should be 0 calling the
function get length you can see that it
函数获取长度，您可以看到它确实返回0，因此可以覆盖push pop
does return 0 so that covers push pop
and length of an array pop removes the
如果要执行以下操作，则数组的长度和pop的长度将删除数组的最后一个元素
last element of an array if you want to
remove an element from the middle of the
从数组的中间删除一个元素，您需要做其他的事情，所以
array you got to do something else so
let's go over that again we want to be
让我们再来看一遍，我们希望能够使用混音对其进行测试，因此我们
able to test it using remix so we're
gonna first create a public function
首先要创建一个包含删除功能的公共功能
that wraps the functionality of removing
the element from an array we're gonna
数组中的元素，我们将其命名为我们移动的函数，它是
name this function we move and it's
gonna take in the index of the array
要接受我们要删除的数组元素的索引
element that we want to remove to remove
an element from array you start with the
数组中的元素，以关键字delete开头，后跟名称
keyword delete followed by the name of
the array that we're gonna remove the
我们要从中删除元素的数组是我的数组
element from in our case it's my array
followed by two brackets and inside the
其次是两个括号，在括号内，我们放置了索引，所以在这里
brackets we put the index so here we're
telling solidity to delete the data
告诉实体删除该索引处的数组的数据存储
store that my array at this index by the
way this is also the same syntax to get
这也是获取值存储区的相同语法
the value store that is
cific index in array now let's try
现在，让我们尝试调用数组中的cific索引，然后继续操作
calling the remove function so go ahead
and recompile and redeploy the contract
重新编译并重新部署合同我要再推三个数字
I'm gonna push three numbers again
let's try removing the second element so
让我们尝试删除第二个元素，以便我们调用remove函数
we're gonna call the remove function
index one now deleting the element from
索引一现在从数组中删除该元素不会更改其长度
array does not change the length of the
array this is because when you call
数组，这是因为当您在数组的索引处调用delete时，它会设置
delete on the array at an index it sets
the value at the end X to a default
结束处的值X为默认值，结束时的默认值为
value the default value for you end is
zero so when we call the function remove
零，所以当我们调用函数remove时，将我的数组的值设置为X
it set the value of my array and X equal
1 to 0 which is the default value of
1到0，这是youant的默认值，所以我只是向您展示了如何
youant so I just showed you how to
delete elements from array and deleting
从数组删除元素和从数组删除元素不会改变
an element from array does not change
the length of the array now I want to
现在我想告诉你一个技巧来保持数组的长度
show you one trick to keep your array
compact what I mean by compact is that
我所说的紧凑是从数组中删除元素
removing the element from our array will
shrink the length of the array and
缩小数组的长度，因为数组变小了
because the array gets smaller this
means that there is no space for deleted
意味着删除元素没有空间保留数组的技巧
elements the trick to keep an array
compact is to copy the last element into
compact是将最后一个元素复制到要删除的索引中
the index that you want to delete for
example let's say that I have an array
例如，假设我有一个元素数组1 2＆3＆4，我想
of elements 1 2 & 3 & 4 and I want to
remove the second element we will copy
删除第二个元素，我们将最后一个元素4复制到
the last element which is 4 into the
second position and then remove the last
第二个位置，然后删除最后一个元素，让我们在代码中看到
element let's see this in code let's
create a new contract
创建一个新合约，我们需要一个数组来存储值和一个
we need an array to store values and a
function to remove elements from the
如前所述，从数组中删除元素的函数
array as explained earlier we first need
to get the last element of the array and
获取数组的最后一个元素，这是下一步的操作，我们需要
this is how you do it next we need to
copy this value over to the position
将此值复制到删除该位置的位置
that were removing the position that
we're removing is my array index so we
我们要删除的是我的数组索引，所以我们将Babeu索引分配给最后一个
assign my Babeu index to the last
element of the array and then we remove
数组的元素，然后我们删除最后一个元素，现在让我们对其进行测试
the last element now let's test this out
and instead of manually pushing values
而不是手动将值推入数组中以删除元素，然后
into array removing the element and then
checking the values afterwards that's
之后检查值是正确的您的功能
right your function to
do all of this for us so you'll create a
为我们完成所有这些操作，因此您将创建一个称为test和push的公共函数
public function called test and push
some values into my array
一些值进入我的数组，接下来我们将删除索引处的元素
next we'll remove the element at index
equal one
除去元素后等于一
after removing the element the ratio now
store one four and three so you'll read
存储一四和三，所以您将阅读一些断言来断言
some assertions to assert that the
length of the array is equal to three
数组的长度等于三，并且顺序为下一个输入
and the order is one for entry next
we'll remove the last element and after
我们将删除最后一个元素，删除最后一个元素后，比率
removing the last element the ratio I'll
store one and four so again we'll write
存储一个和四个，所以我们再次写一些关于长度和
some assertions about the length and
order of the array we assert that the
数组的顺序，我们断言数组的长度现在等于2
length of the array is now equal to two
and that the order is one and then for
并且该命令是一个命令，然后现在编译并部署一个紧凑数组
now compile and deployed a compact array
contract call the test function and you
合同调用测试功能，您可以看到该功能成功完成，
can see that the function succeeded so
that covers how to remove elements from
涵盖如何在保持数组紧凑的同时从数组中删除元素
array while keeping the array compact
in this video we went over how to create
在本视频中，我们讨论了如何创建数组可以声明为固定数组
an array arrays can be declared as fixed
size or dynamically sized arrays have
大小或动态大小的数组具有三个内置功能push pop
three built-in functionalities push pop
and Bank and the leaving the element
银行和离开元素在数组和一个技巧中造成了差距
creates a gap in the array and one trick
to keep the array compact is to move the
保持数组紧凑是将最后一个元素移到要删除的地方
last element into the place to delete
that's the basic topics of array that I
这是我想在本视频中介绍的数组的基本主题
wanted to cover in this video if you
have any questions let me know in the
有任何问题请在下面的评论中让我知道，谢谢收看
comments below thanks for watching have
a nice week and I'll see you in the next
美好的一周，我会在下一个视频中再见
video